遨游天地间作品  淡淡风倾情奉献
From：Aoyou tiandijian and dandanfeng
云 卷 云 舒 任 遨 游        花 开 花 落 天 地 间
别动!
Don't move!
趴在车上
Hands on the car,
双腿分开 让我搜身
spread your legs.
警官 什么事?
Sir,what's the matter?
半夜三更形迹可疑
You're stealthy here!
是不是想偷车?
Are you going to steal this car?
我想偷车?
What?
这车…是我的
This is my car.
我刚才是被我的客人追啊
I have been chased after by my client.
半夜三更是什么客人追你啊?
What client do you mean?
我…
I…
你是拉皮条的吧?
I think you must be a pimper.
我拉皮条?
What?
像我这么有气质的人…
I am a gentleman,
我哪里像拉皮条?
how come you claim me as a pimper!
你全身上下就像拉皮条的
You're like a pimper!
全身上下都像?
What?Am I like a pimper?
当然啦!
Sure!
警官…
Sir…
你干什么?
What are you doing?
我只是想拿一张名片给你
I just want to give you my name card.
慢慢来…
Slow down…
警官 是这样的
In fact,
其实我是在殡仪馆里当营业主任
I am a sales manager of a funeral home,
这是我的名片
this is my card.
祥福殡仪…殡仪馆啊?
Funeral home…Funeral home?
是啊
Yes.
那刚才是什么客人追你啊?
So,what client was chasing after you?
刚才…是一个刚刚仙游的客人在追我
A client who has just died.
你吓我是吧?
Are you bluffing?
当然不是啊…
Of course not!I…
你干什么?
What are you doing?
我打算让你听首歌…
I just want to let you hear a song,
舒缓一下情绪
to make you relax.
关掉!…
Turn it off…
这是你们署长说的…
The Commissioner of Police said,
听歌可以减轻压力啊
music can lessen pressure.
要不然我换一首帝女花让你听好了
Well,why not change a Cantonese opera for you instead?
署长他说过吗?
Did our head say such thing?
对!是你们署长他这样说的
Sure!Your commissioner did say that openly.
他说过那就听吧!好像还蛮好听的
Well,it sounds nice!
警官 要是没什么事的话
If you don't have any more question,
那我就先走了
may I leave now?
好好 你走吧…
Alright,
开车小心一点
Alright,drive carefully.
谢谢你啊 警官
Thank you,sir.
不客气
You're welcome.
要是有什么需要的话 打电话给我
If you have any needs,just call me.
我觉得我们两个…蛮投缘的
It's predestined to know you,isn't it?
是啊 蛮谈得来的!
I think we can be good friends.
就是啊!
That's right,
我给你打个八折好了
I'll give you a 20% discount if necessary.
谢了啊!
Thank you.
不客气!
You're welcome.
好 过两天我打电话给你
I'll call you later.
拜拜
Bye bye.
先生 你的皮包
Hey,you've forgotten your briefcase.
差点忘了!
Oh,thank you.
拜拜!
Bye bye.Take care.
小心一点啊
保重啊!
Take care!
你打电话给我什么事啊?
What's the matter?
那个王百万他就要死了!
Wong Pak-man is going to die.
王百万?
Wong Pak-man?
长方实业的那个王百万?
The billionaire?
就是他!
That's right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
大头文 你不是想捷足先登吧?
Man,are you going to take my advantage?
行有行规
In our field,
双日你的
we'd follow our own regulations,
单日我的
business in single day will go to me.
今…今天还是双日啊?
But today is…isn't the single day,
十一时五十分而已
see,it's 11:50 pm only.
还是我的!
The business will go to me.
看谁幸运啦
Let's see who is more lucky.
护士?!
Nurse?!
先不要死
Don't die!
快…快死!
Die!Die now!
死!
Die!
死…死!
Die…
死!
Go to hell…
死啊…快死
Go to hell at once!
医生?!
Doctor?
过了十二点 单日啊!
12 am,single day,huh!
姐姐 节哀顺变啦!
Sister,come on!Don't be upset.
不能丢下我啊!
Don't leave me alone!
王太太 节哀顺变
Mrs.Wong,don't be upset.
王先生他英年早逝…
Mr.Wong died young…
英什么年早什么逝啊?
What?
我姐夫七十多岁了
My brother-in-law was 70 and something.
我的意思是说王先生他英…
I mean he was comparatively young…
不是 英雄这么早死…
to die at this age.
真的不太好!
Have my consolation.
你是谁啊?
Who are you?
我是殡仪馆的营业主任
I am the sales manager of the funeral home,
我叫郑力
my name is Cheng Lik.
我觉得呢…
Well,
王先生对香港的前景是充满信心
Mr.Wong had full confidence with the future of Hong Kong,
又运筹帷幄 高瞻远瞩
he was a farsighted strategist in business.
实在是我们后辈学习的好榜样
Mr.Wong really is a good sample for the young people.
所以我觉得王先生的后事
That's why I think Mr.Wong's funeral…
应该办得风风光光 体体面面
should be a great one.
不知道两位觉得我说得对不对?
What do you think?
我不知道啊
I have no idea,
阿标 你来作主
Bill,please take care of it.
丧礼一定要办得体体面面
Bear in mind that,
我们可不能丢人
the funeral should be a great one.
钱不是问题 最重要是面子
Money isn't a problem,we need face.
全香港的人都认识百万
Everyone in Hong Kong knows my husband.
我知道…
Sure…
不知道这位先生贵姓?
May I know your name?
我姓陈
Chan.
陈先生
Mr.Chan.
叫我舅舅好了
Just call me uncle.
舅舅 你有什么需要尽管吩咐
Uncle,please tell me what should be done,
我一定会尽全力把这个丧事办好
I'll do it accordingly.
好了 我知道
It's alright,I know what to do.
我带客人来看点东西
I am showing my customer around.
好 随便看
OK,you see.
舅舅…
Uncle,
这烧纸钱绝对不可以省
for the paper sacrificial gifts,it's a must.
一定要多烧一点才代表尊重先人
More you burn,more respect to the dead.
怎样才算多?
How much should be burnt?
舅舅…
Uncle,
我来介绍一个基本的特别套餐给你
Let me show you the basic set.
你看它包含了些什么…
这个基本套餐它包括有花园洋房…
It includes house,
金山银山 望乡台 墓亭…
gold mine,silver mine,
一对轿夫 一对金童玉女…
Farewell pavilion and four servants.
一个保险箱 一个衣柜…
A safe,a wardrobe,
这些加起来一共是…一万五千块!
total is…$15,000.It's rather cheap.
这怎么可以!太寒酸了!
No way!
我们可是上流社会的人
We are rich to deserve more.
这是我的职责所在
This is my duty
我一定要给你介绍一下
to introduce the cheapest set to you,
王先生生前这么样的富有…
however,Mr.Wong is so rich,
我想他仙逝之后一定不能住小房子
he won't live a small house after his death.
我们应该烧个大洋房给他
So,we must burn him a big villa.
既然这房子大 自然这桥就不能窄
So,he shouldn't deserve a narrow bridge.
所以我们一定要烧一个大桥给他
That's why we should prepare a wide bridge for him.
没错
Sure.
王先生这样仙游
Mr.Wong died,
我担心他可能会寂寞是不是
I worry that he would feel lonely.
所以我会烧两个小老婆给他
So I will burn him two concubines.
有了小老婆
And then,
这别墅就一定不能少
he should have a big villa to settle the concubines.
所以我随时烧两三个别墅给他
So,I will burn him two or three more houses.
有了这么多别墅和大房子
And,servants should be provided.
这佣人也一定不能少
servants should be provided.
所以我会烧个厨师…
I will burn some chefs,
园丁 甚至菲佣还有…
gardener and maids to him.
慢着!菲佣不行!
Wait,no Philippine maids,
我姐夫他听不懂英文
my brother-in-law doesn't know English.
没关系
Never mind,
那烧一些会讲中文的菲佣给他
I'll burn him some maids who know Cantonese.
真的?没骗我
Really?
真的!
Sure.
王先生生前会不会开车?
Does Mr.Wong know driving?
干嘛要开车?他司机多的是
He had drivers.
这我也猜到了!
So,
所以这司机和豪车这些也都不能少
drivers and deluxe cars should be burnt too.
电器我也准备好了
I have prepared electric appliances too.
电器我会烧给他CD LD…
Say,CD,LD,
还有DVD 全烧给他
and DVD too.
DVD这么先进也可以烧?
DVD?Isn't it too high-tech for the old?
对啊!再烧一份中文说明书给他
A user's guide will be burnt too,of course,
就可以了
a Cantonese version.
真细心啊!
You're so caring,
那么一共多少钱?
well,how much should we spend?
加起来不过十七万五
Total is $175,000 only.
你最好算便宜点
You'd better give us a discount,
这不是钱的问题
money isn't a problem,
这关系到我们的面子问题
it's the matter of face.
我知道…
I know,
最近已经是殡仪馆的特惠月
since we are offering special discount in this month,
所以我已经帮你打了六折了
actually I've already given you a 40% off.
十七万五其实不算贵
It's not expensive at all.
不过我跟舅舅你特别有缘
But you are so nice,
就算十七万好了
I'll cut the price to $170,000.
你可真会做生意
You're a man of the world.
还有一个很重要的问题…
But one very important question.
王先生他生前有没有什么儿女?
Does Mr.Wong have children?
没有
No.
真的没有儿女啊?
Really?
没有
No.
那不就没有人替他哭丧?
Well,so no one would cry for him in his funeral.
那也没办法啊
I can't help.
这个你也不用担心
Don't worry,
我可以请人替他哭丧
I can hire keener for him.
纯流泪一千…
Only weeping,a thousand,
流鼻涕的二千
with tears,just two thousand.
这可要算人头啊
Per head.
一千元一个这么便宜啊?
It's cheap!
那来两个好了
So give me two.
灵堂那么大 多几个人哭丧才有气氛
The funeral should have someone to cry.
我一定会请样子英俊…
Sure,I will find you a handsome one,
而且是家世清白
with no tattoo.
真的?要有气质的啊!
Really?You should find some decent looking ones.
千万不要像穷鬼啊
I don't want those who look poor.
像我!…可以吧
They will be as decent looking as I am.
红姐 你看看
Sister Hung,
这样可不可以啊?
is that OK?
当然不可以啦!
Of course not,
头上的腊涂得不够多
the wax isn't enough.
这尸体从冷藏库出来
When the body is out from the fridge,
一边出来一边渗水
water will leak out.
这个腊要是涂得不够多的话
If you don't put enough wax,
就不容易上妆
the cosmetic will be useless.
要涂在哪些位置你晓不晓得?
More wax,where should you fill?
要涂在那些罅缝和洞洞里头
Fill those holes,
堵住它 知道吗?
got it?
红姐…
Sister Hung…
我今天可不可以早点走啊?
May I leave earlier?
我晚上有事啊
I have something personal to do tonight.
看你这个样子!约女朋友了?
Do you have a date?
不是啊
No,
陈美丽今天晚上在 AC Hall…
I am going to attend the mini concert…
有个迷你演唱会
of Beauty Chan tonight.
我好不容易弄到一张票 我准备…
It's not easy to get the ticket…
那个陈美丽啊?
Who is Beauty Chan?
她长得不错 不过她唱歌好难听
She is nice looking,but she sings badly.
你说什么?
What did you say?
你不用那么凶啊?
Don't be that serious.
不要生她的气 她是新来的
Don't get angry,she is a new comer.
我告诉你 陈美丽是他的超级偶像
Beauty Chan is his idol.
我打你啊!
I'll beat you,you know?
他是她的歌迷啊
Super fan.
你不要乱说话
Mind your tongue!
知道了…
I know it,I know it.
这里啊 怎么还有个洞啊
Stuff that hole too.
我请大家吃蛋挞
I'll treat you to tarts.
这么好啊!
You're so nice!
我接了一单大买卖
I've done a big business.
真的 有多大?
How big?
王百万你说大不大?
Wong Pak-man!
王百万?这下发了!
Wong Pak-man?You're rich!
要比原来大三倍啊
You can earn 3 times than normal.
发财了!知不知道王百万是谁?
Do you know who Wong Pak-man is?
正点!
It's great.
我讲了几次啊?
How many times I've told you?
活人的钱可以赚
You can earn living people's money,
死人钱不要骗
but don't cheat the dead.
人家给了钱
They paid,
你们要好好干知不知道
so you should work accordingly.
知道…你说得对
You're right…
她是新来的
She is the new comer.
你好 我是阿Ann 新来的
How are you?I am Ann.
我很喜欢化妆
I love making up.
喜欢替别人化妆
I love making up for others,
也喜欢帮自己化妆
and making up for myself.
不好意思!
I am sorry.
刚才多亏昌哥帮忙 让我实习
Cheung is so nice to be my model.
阿力来了吗?
Has Lik come?
你们拿着头干什么?
Why are you holding the head of the dead?
死者为大
Respect the dead!
尊重一下过世的人啊!
这位先人被三十多个人围杀
This guy was chopped in a gang fight,
砍成二十多段 尸体都肢离破碎
his body was divided into twenty parts.
像堆积木一样!
Like Legos,
我要一块一块的把他拼好
I have to waste time to gather it.
随便你啊 快点弄好
Up to you!Wash your hands…
把手洗干净然后去餐厅吃饭
and come to the canteen to join us.
走了…
Let's go…
红姐 我还是不去了
Sister Hung,
我把东西收拾好
I think I have to stay and tidy up first.
好
Alright.
可是…
But…
可不可以找个人陪我啊?
Can anyone give me company?
我陪你
I'll stay with you.
我先把头洗干净
But I should wash the head first.
我下去吃蛋挞
I am going to eat tarts,handle the body please.
好的…
Alright…
等等我!
Wait for me!
你们看什么?
What's up?
这是我今天第一餐啊
This is my first meal of this day.
你怎么搞得那么惨啊?
Why are you so poor?
我才不算惨呢!
I am not poor at all,
他和肾亏才叫惨
Trump and Sun-kwai are much more poorer!
这两个人欠华哥的赌马钱
They lost much money in horse racing,
还没还 随时会被砍死
they still owe Wah a lot.They'll be killed.
你搞什么 欠华哥钱啊?
How dare you owe Wah's money?
真的会砍死你的!
He will chop you to death!
力哥 有没有什么外快可以捞啊?
Brother Lik,do you have any moon-lighting job?
当孝子怎么样?
How about being a keener?
我干啊!什么价钱?
I love to!How about the pay?
纯流泪 五百…
Only weeping,five hundred,
加上眼泪鼻涕 一千
with tears,a thousand.
那要是吐血呢?
How about vomitting blood?
吐血?
Blood?
吐血的话那就拿去捐啊
You'd better donate it.
我真是不明白这些人…
I don't understand why people cry…
为什么要死了才哭个死去活来
after the death of their relatives and friends.
不能潇洒一点吗?
Why can't people be a bit carefree?
高见!…
You're so wise!
挡棺!
Stop the coffin!
爸爸…
Daddy…
爸爸 你不要离开我啊…
Daddy…Don't leave me!
你不要走啊!
Don't leave me!
我们好想你啊!
I am going to miss you!
爸爸 你不要离开我啊…
Daddy…Don't leave me!
你怎么可以离开我啊!
Don't leave us!
不要拉我 我要爸爸!
Don't…Daddy…
我们好爱你啊爸爸!
We love you,daddy!
不要离开我们!
Don't leave us!
苍天没眼啊!
God is merciless!
天妒英才啊!
God is jealous of you!
英年早逝啊
Daddy dies young!
沉冤待雪啊…
Who will avenge you?
爸爸 我要帮你报仇啊!
Daddy,I wanna take revenge for you!
我要帮你报仇!
I want to avenge you!
我一定要帮你报仇!
Daddy,I want to avenge you!
他们说什么?
What did they say?
他们好像是说要报仇啊!
Revenge,I guess!
怎么那两个家伙口口声声说什么…
Why did they call…
什么报仇啊?
Why did they call for revenge?
我姐夫他是病死的
My brother-in-law died of sickness.
他们可能是太投入太激动
Maybe they are too excited,
所以讲错话了
so…They said something wrong.
叫他们收敛一点
You'd better ask them to behave themselves.
好 我会教训
Sure I will.
你们两个今天看起来怎么那么配啊
You two look like a perfect match.
来…照张像啊
Come on,I'll take a picture for you.
这样也叫配啊
You mean this a perfect match?
你们俩靠近一点
Stay closer.
不用惊奇 正式介绍
Relax,let me introduce to you all.
她是我女朋友 Elaine
My girlfriend,Elaine.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
不用拘束 她知道我做什么的
Just relax,she knows what I am.
来!坐!
Please sit down.
搞什么鬼啊!这么晚才来!
Bastard,why do you come late?
Elaine是吧!你好
Drink it.
来 我们一起庆祝敬爱的力哥
To Brother Lik,for he has given us…
又找到大户关照我们赚了一笔
for he has given us a chance to make money!
好 来干杯!
Cheers!
万岁万岁
Long life to us.
万万岁!
Long life!
你干什么?
What's the matter with you?
是不是受了什么刺激啊?
What's the problem?
正不正点啊?
Isn't it nice?
我整整弄了两个小时
I've done this for over two hours.
你怎么弄了那么久啊?
Next time,don't waste too much time for making up.
下次啊轻轻弄就好了
Just a bit make up would do.
化妆可是很高深的
You won't understand,
讲了你也不会明白的
making up is a serious matter.
不讲了
You will never understand.
那我跟你讲 这是我女朋友Elaine
This is my girlfriend,Elaine.
你好
Hello…
我叫阿Ann 我好喜欢化妆
My name is Ann,I love making up so much.
如果你需要人家帮你化妆…
If you have any needs,
改改造型的话
or want to change your image,
就打电话给我
just call me.
谢了…
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
阿力前一阵子有一笔外快…
Lik gave me chance…
让我们赚了一点钱
Lik gave me chance for moon-lighting.
你看 送给你的
So,this present is for you.
好漂亮呀!
It's pretty!
喜不喜欢?
Like it?
真是好货色啊
This is nice!
我看看
Let me take a look.
蛮漂亮的
It's nice.
可是啊…
But…
总是有那么一点…
什么啊?
What?
该怎么说呢?
What should I say?
我看看…
Let me take a look.
我知道了 是不是土了一点啊!
It's a little bit out-dated!
对…
Yeah…
土了一点…
It's out-dated.
什么东西?我看看
Let me take a look.
不要乱说啊?
No way!
有没有搞错啊?
Are you kidding?
街上捡来的东西送给别人…
You picked it in the garbage bin…
你有没有毛病啊?
and send it as gift,right?
来 给你!
This is for you.
你不要乱说啊?
What?
那么容易捡的话那你捡给我看看!
Why don't you pick one from the garbage bin for me?
好棒呀!
It's great!
你的唢吶吹得真不错
You play Chinese clarionet well.
唢吶吗?
Chinese clarionet?
阿力 阿堂
Hi,Lik,Shishedo,
你看看我送些什么东西给你啊!
see what I have got for you.
厉害呀!
It's great!
真的假的?
Isn't it true?
是陈美丽亲笔签名的海报啊
It's the poster with Beauty Chan's autograph.
正点啊!
It's great!
这名字是不是你自己签的?
Did you sign the name?
再怎么说我也是音乐圈的人嘛
I am a musician,
一张海报算什么?
it's a piece of cake for me to get her poster.
Daviv!
阿力
Hi,Lik.
好久没见…
Long time no see…
给我一张名片吧
Give me your card,
不然的话 我怎么找你?
or how can I find you?
我今天没带 下次给你…
I haven't got any here,I'll give it to you next time.
没关系 待会留个电话给我就好了
Write me your phone number,that's it.
好…
Alright…
你有好多朋友在那边啊
You have a gathering over there,haven't you?
来 我给你介绍一下
Oh yes,come and join us.
各位…先安静一下 不要吵…
Everyone, please be quiet.
我的老同学 叫什么名字?
This is my old classmate,what's your name?
我叫 Daviv
Daviv.
懂了… Daviv嘛
I know,Daviv!
我做金融的
I work in the financial field.
金融界的啊
I see.
你好 我叫阿昌
Hi,I am Cheong,
正宗传统粤曲界的
I sing Cantonese Opera.
我叫百搭
Trump,
演艺界运动界我都是全能的…
I work in the entertainment…
所以叫百搭
and sports field.
这是我的女朋友 Elaine
This is my girlfriend,Elaine.
嗨
Hi.
我叫…
My name is…
肾亏!
Sun-kwai!
他本来是跟我一样 全能的
Actually,he is as capable as I am,
可怜他的肾就有那么一点点…没用!
but,poor him,his kidneys are…useless.
我叫阿Rock 音乐界的
I am Rock,I am a musician.
只要能放进嘴巴的我都能吹响
I can play any musical instrument by mouth.
Hello 我叫阿Ann 我是美容界的
Hello,I am Ann,I am a beautician.
魔界的!
No,she is a devil!
我也是美容界的 资生堂
Me too,call me Shishedo.
这位是…
This is…
叫我阿红 我也是美容界的
I am Hung,I am a beautician too.
你好
Nice to meet you.
你只跟她握手?
You just shake hands with her!
我们也要握手!
We want to shake hands too.
大家握个手 做个好朋友
Be good friends!
别说那么多 来干杯…
Cut the crap,let's cheers!Come on.
阿红 干杯
Hung,cheers!
祝每一个都快乐
Everybody happy!
一起快乐
Happy together!
你也会讲英文啊!
You spoke English too.
对不起啊
I'm sorry!
陈美丽?
Beauty Chan?
我是你的歌迷啊
I am your fan!
我有你的海报 还有你的亲笔签名
See,I have your poster and your autograph too.
我可不可以跟你照张相?
May I take a picture with you?
我有带照相机
I have my own camera.
来 照个相啊
Let's take a picture.
走了?
She's left that quickly!
让一让…
Give way…
请问 什么事啊?
What's the matter?
就是那个歌星陈美丽 她死了
Beauty Chan died!
她昨晚出车祸
She was killed in a car accident,
整个车都散了
her car became a mess.
呼了你一天都不回个电话?
Why didn't you return my call?
对不起 我是职员…
I am the staff…
你们好
How are you?
好了 不要太伤心 节哀顺变
Don't be too upset!
请问你是…
You are…
我是郑力 是殡仪馆的营业主任
Cheng Lik,the sales manager of the funeral home.
我是专门来协助两位的
I come to see whether I can help.
您是陈太太是吧
Are you Mrs.Chan?
陈太太 不要太伤心 身体要紧
Don't be too upset,health is more important.
妈妈 别哭了
Don't be too upset.
这位是…
This is…
我是美丽的姐姐
I am Beauty's elder sister.
啊!陈小姐
Miss Chan,
你介不介意我提供意见给你?
would you mind me giving you some advice?
你说
Well.
这个美丽在她最风光的时刻过世了
Beauty died when she was a rising star.
社会各界人士或者是她的歌迷们…
All of her fans…
影迷们都会非常的想念她
are going to miss her.
所以我们一定要…
That's why,
把这个丧礼办得风风光光
her funeral should be a great one.
让她在歌迷心目中留下个美好的印象
So as to leave the best image for her fans.
不晓得两位觉得我说的对不对?
Don't you agree?
妈
Mom
对啊 一定要把你妹妹的葬礼…
Yes,you'd do the best for her funeral.
办得体体面面的
you'd do the best for her funeral.
我知道
I will,mom.
郑先生 我想不止是这个葬礼
Mr.Cheng,not only the funeral,
我们还希望…
we wish you…
你能把我妹妹也弄得好看一点!
to make my sister's face look better too.
好看一点?!
Look better?
我尽力而为
I will try my best.
喂 化妆间
Dressing Room.
怎么了?力哥
Brother Lik,it's you.
力哥说陈美丽死了
Beauty Chan died.
陈美丽死了?
Beauty Chan died?
红姐…
Sister Hung…
那个陈美丽死了
Beauty Chan died.
什么?
What?
陈美丽死了呀!
Beauty Chan died.
陈美丽死掉了?
Beauty Chan died?
是啊 力哥说的
Yes,Lik told me that.
好啊!
It's great!
可以去信和炒卖她的照片了!
I can sell her pictures at a higher price.
陈美丽死了…
Beauty Chan died…
阿堂 我是百搭
Shishedo,this is Trump.
百搭 什么事啊?
Trump?
我告诉你 你的超级偶像陈美丽死了
Your idol Beauty Chan died.
不要开玩笑了!
Stop kidding!
昨天晚上我们分手了以后
Last night,
我在街上遇到了她
I saw her on the road after leaving the bar.
还跟她拍了一张照片
I took a picture with her too.
昨天晚上一点半的时候她撞车死掉了
She was killed in a car accident at 1 am last night.
不相信啊?打开电视看看吧
Don't you believe it?Turn on the TV.
好…
Alright…
神经病!
You're nuts!
接着是本港新闻
This is the local news,
昨晚零晨一点三十分
at 1:30 am last night,
名歌星陈美丽…
the famous singer Beauty Chan…
在一次交通意外中伤重死亡
died in a car accident.
当时陈美丽正驾车途经公主道
She drove her car along the Princess Margaret Road,
怀疑汽车失控…
it's suspected that she lost control…
撞向路边…
of her car and got a crash.
当医护人员抢救途中证实死亡
She was found death on the way to hospital.
至于车祸发生的原因…
As to the cause of the accident…
不可能!昨晚四点我才见过她
Impossible!I saw her at four am last night.
好!我们到了 下车
Beauty,we are moving in.Here we are.
用力点
Let's go.
慢慢来…
Take care…
兄弟 帮忙关下车门好不好
Pal,close the door please.
陈美丽 走吧
Beauty Chan,let's go.
陈美丽 我们要进去了
Let's go in.Beauty Chan…
让一让…
Give way…
让一让…到了
Give way,here we are.
陈美丽 我们到了
Beauty Chan,here we are.
到了 请让一让
Here we are,give way…
安安乐乐 让一让路
Feel at ease,give way…
小心
Take care.
好!
Fine!
这里冷气开放
Have a nice sleep,
你可以睡得舒舒服服的
it's air-conditioned.
等一下…
Wait…
干嘛?
What's up?
什么东西啊?
What the hell is it?
跟她拍个照啊!
We can make much money…
卖给杂志社可以赚许多钱啊!
by selling her picture to the press.
神经病!会捱老板骂的!
You nuts!The boss would scold us.
骂就骂我好了!关你什么事?
I will be the one to be scolded,
你快点拍啊!
just do it,hurry up!
你说的啊 要骂就骂你!
I am just giving you a hand,
不关我的事情啊!
none of my business.
快点!
Come on!
你一定要多多包涵
Please forgive me.
陈美丽的尸体送来了吗?
Is Beauty Chan's body here?
送来了 在这里啊
Yes,it is right here.
就是这个
This is her body.
你干什么?
What are you doing here?
没什么
Nothing.
你偷拍照啊?
Are you taking her picture?
他叫我拍的
He told me to take it.
你搞什么?
What are you doing?
你干嘛拍她照片?
Why do you want her picture?
你们拍美丽照片要干什么?
How dare you!
没有啊!
I didn't do that.
肾亏叫我拍的
Sun-kwai asked me to do it,
不关我的事情 你干嘛那么用力啊
it's none of my business!
你们两个到底搞什么鬼啊?
Are you sick?
干什么?
What's happening?
什么事啊
What's the matter?
他们两个偷拍美丽的照片!
They took Beauty's picture!
干嘛要这样呢?
Are you kidding?
你搞什么?为什么要拍她照片?
Why do you do that?
肾亏叫我帮她拍的
Sun-kwai asked me to take it for him.
他叫你去死你死不死啊?
What's wrong with you?
我说过[死者为大]!
I've told you,always respect the dead.
拍都已经拍了 大不了下次…
But it's already done,maybe next time…
红姐你看!怎会这样子?
What's up?Sister Hung,what's wrong?
大腿已经放开 还抓着裤子
She is still holding my trousers.
好痛啊…
It hurts!
尸体有时候会这样子!
Because of muscle contraction,
因为肌肉收缩的关系
the body will move sometimes.
所以要有心理准备
So,you'd be prepared when you work,
不要怕
don't panic.
好痛啊
It hurts!
你们…
Hurry up!It hurts!
有没有剪刀啊?
Do you have scissors?
有 剪刀…
Yes,scissors…
好痛呀…
It hurts!
你不要动啊
Don't move!
不然我剪到你我不管啊!
It'll hurt you.
小心点…
Take care…
看着点…
Watch out…
我那个地方有没有受伤…
It hurts…
有怪莫怪 这下你知道痛了吧
Forgive me please.
你帮帮忙拿点药来擦一下好不好!
Give me some medicine,it really hurts.
快去换条裤子吧
Go change your pants.
快点吧
Hurry up!
谢谢你的剪刀 谢谢
Thank you for your scissors.
不客气
You're welcome.
阿红 陈美丽的尸体会比较难画
Hung,Beauty Chan's make up is a difficult job.
你也知道丧家很重视
You know,her family is demanding.
好歹也是个明星嘛
Anyways,she is a famous pop singer.
阿力 还是让我来做吧?
Lik,why not let me do it?
红姐!
Sister Hung!
也好!
That's a good idea,
他是陈美丽的忠实歌迷
he is the loyal fan of Beauty Chan,
帮自己偶像做事会比较用心一点
sure he will pay more attention to work for her.
你既然有信心就给你做
If you are confident,just go ahead.
好!阿力 谢谢你!
Thank you so much!
你怎么了?
How are you?
好痛啊!
It hurts!
你活该!
Serve you right.
再多捏一点
If her hand moved a bit,
你不只肾亏 那儿都没了
your dick would have been finished.
真想不到殡仪馆的禁忌这么应验
I shouldn't have done that!
当然啦!
Of course!
哪个王八蛋乱丢东西啊?
Who dropped that thing?
上头没人住啊
No body is living up there.
那我们干嘛走这里呢?
So why do we come this way?
我跟着你走的
I just follow you.
是我跟着你走的
I follow you.
对不起 谢谢…
Please give way…
请让一让…
Give way…
陈美丽的脸撞成那个样子
Beauty Chan's got a broken face,
我担心他搞不定啊
I worry that he can't make it.
要重新把她的脸做得像以前那么美丽
If they want her face to be as beautiful as it was,
我也是有点担心
I can't make it too.
但是如果要做得整整齐齐…
But if they want it…
可以见人的话
to be ready for seen,
这点我倒对他有信心
I think he can make it.
我是怕他自我要求太高了
I worry that Shishedo would be too demanding.
就算高也没办法啊
But he can't help!
反正尽力而为就是了
He just has to try his best.
我想这点他会懂的
I think he will understand it.
连吃饭的时间都没有
I am too busy to eat.
有生意了?
Business time?
天气转凉 生意特别好
Yes,the weather changed,so business will go well.
明心医院的大婶Call我…
The maid in Ming Sum Hospital called me…
说有个老伯差不多了
that a granny is dying.
那我们买单啦
So,check now.
不需要!反正菜已经点了 你先吃嘛
No,you'd better eat the food first.
什么?
What?
起码可以少浪费一半啊
Don't waste your food.
走了
See you.
这么巧啊!
What a coincidence to meet you here.
我约了朋友在这儿吃饭
I dated my friend here.
我有事我先走了
I am in a hurry,see you.
有事啊?
Good bye then.
有时间我给你电话
I'll call you later.
好的
OK.
那么巧呀 一个人?
Nice to meet you,are you alone?
本来不是 现在是
Actually no,but now,yes.
你呢?
How about you?
我约了朋友在这儿吃饭 不过…
I dated my friend,but…
他好像还没来
I think he comes late.
如果你朋友还没来
Why not have
可以坐下来先喝杯东西啊?
a drink with me?
好啊
Alright.
嗨 陈美丽
Beauty Chan,
问你一个有点尴尬的问题
may I ask you an embarrassing question?
你觉得你自己算不算爱美?
Don't you think you care your image too much?
不只是爱美 我简直是非常的爱美
Sure!I care my image very much.
其实我们做歌者的
I am an artist,
有这么多歌迷支持
so many fans are supporting me,
打扮得漂亮一点也算是尊重他们
so I should respect them by dressing well.
他们看了也会很开心啊
They will be happy to see me dressing beautifully.
将来就算我死了
In fact,when I die,
我也想死得漂漂亮亮的
I want to die beautifully.
[[无人午夜 在忘形亲近抱紧你[[
[[I hold you tight in the lonely night.[[
[[无人午夜[[
[[Lonely night,[[
[[梦仍然思念妄想你[[
[[I miss you in my dream.[[
[[再没法可变心 愿缠住你[[
[[I can't stop myself from loving you,
[[愿迷住你心神[[
[[I wish to capture you.[[
[[我为你痴心[[
[[I love you![[
[[无人午夜[[
[[Lonely night,[[
[[在忘形挑逗爱抚你[[
[[I can't help seducing and touching you.[[
陈美丽…
Beauty Chan…
[[溶化身躯 让灵魂依附你体里[[
[[My body melts for you.[[
[[烫热你冰冷心[[
[[To heat your cold heart,[[
[[日随着你 夜陪着你 跟你…[[
[[to follow you,day and night…[[
美丽 你好美丽啊!
You're so beautiful!
[[我为你痴心[[
[[I fall for you.[[
[[如今 谁造了这裂痕[[
[[ho made the gap[[
[[再没法可拉近[[
[[between us?[[
[[再没半点缘份[[
[[不可以![[
[[No way![[
[[情真 谁在意阴或阳[[
[[My true love to you,[[
[[注定永相伴随 再续这我缘份[[
[[no matter live or dead.[[
陈美丽?!
Beauty Chan?
我不想死得这么难看
I don't want to die terribly.
你帮帮我
Please help me.
让我死得漂亮一点
Let me die beautifully.
[[定迷住你 定缠住你 冤你[[
[[I will follow you![[
[[迷住你缠住你 迷住你心神[[
[[I will bother you,I will obsess you![[
阿堂
Shishedo,
这个衣服是她家人要给她穿的
this is requested by Beauty's family.
交给你了
Just dress her up.
这妆还不错 可以见人了
This is nice.
继续啊
Go on.
[[迷住你 缠住你[[
[[I will obsess you![[
[[迷住你今生今世未完[[
[[Forever,ever…[[
麻烦让一让…
Give way…
那不就是陈美丽的姐姐嘛
That's Beauty's sister.
能不能让我们见陈美丽最后一面?
May I take a look of Beauty's face?
陈小姐 你先看看
Miss Chan,
要是有什么需要的话呢
just tell me your request.
你尽管开口
We'll do anything you want.
郑先生
Mr.Chan,
我想看我妹妹的妆化得怎么样了
may I look at my sister's make up?
你妹妹的妆已经化得差不多了
It's almost done.
因为你妹妹那个样子…
But your sister's face is…
我明白 郑先生
I understand that,Mr.Chan,
你尽力而为
just try your best.
其实我也准备好…
We are prepared…
必要时不让人瞻仰遗容
not to let other see her face in coffin.
昨天晚上已经看过了
I saw her face last night,
大致上没什么问题
it's alright.
不过到了最后还是要交由你来决定
But you'd make the final decision.
我带你去看她
Let me show you,this way please.
好 谢谢
Thank you.
你认为她这个样子也能见人?
You claim this OK?
我昨天晚上看到不是这个样子
I…it isn't what I saw last night.Sorry…
你…
You…
阿昌…
Cheong…
来了
Yes.
去把阿堂找来
Ask Shishedo to come here right now.
快去啊
Go!
陈小姐 我昨天晚上看到的…
Miss Chan,this isn't what…
的确不是这个样子
I saw last night.
我已经把化妆师找来了
I am asking someone…
他现在马上会帮你处理
to fix it right now.
对不起
I am sorry.
真是不好意思
你搞什么鬼啊?
What's wrong with you?
叫我怎么跟人家交代啊?
How can I explain to Miss Chan?
我先出去颂经
I am leaving for the prayer first.
陈小姐 你放心
Miss Chan,don't worry.
我可以把美丽弄得像从前一样美丽
I can make Beauty as pretty as she was.
你再给我一晚时间
Give me one more night.
我拜托你们好吗!你做得到就做
Please!If you can do it,just go ahead,
做不到告诉我
if not,just tell me.
别跟我说可以 我进来看却不行
You don't have to cheat me.
我说过了
I've said before,
我已经准备好不让人瞻仰遗容
maybe,I won't let people see her face.
只要一晚!
Just one night.
我一定可以把美丽…
I can return her beauty.
弄得像从前一样的漂亮
不过我有个要求
But I have a request.
我希望先让美丽入棺…
I want to put her body inside the coffin…
然后化妆
before making up.
因为化了妆之后…
It's not good…
再把她搬来搬去可能会不太好
to carry her body after the make up.
怎么做随便你了
Just as you said.
阿堂 你搞什么东西啊?
Shishedo,what's wrong with you?
我昨晚看到的…
I didn't see that face last night,
不是这个样子?
what's wrong with you?
你有种敢说美丽昨晚有多漂亮吗?
Dare you tell me she was beautiful last night?
你知道她以前有多美丽啊!
She was so beautiful when she was alive.
我又不是让你…
I didn't ask you…
把她弄得跟以前一样漂亮
to make her beautiful.
只要可以见人就行了
Just do your best to make her be seen.
不相信啊 我办得到
I can make it.
我拜托你 如果你不行
Please,if you can't do it,
叫阿红做好吗?
I will ask Hung to follow it,OK?
陈小姐 你早
Good morning,Miss Chan.
郑先生 谢谢你
Mr.Cheng,thank you so much.
昨天我讲话可能重了一点
I am sorry for what I said yesterday,
希望你别介意
I hope you won't mind.
真的很谢谢你
Thank you so much.
美丽的妆我非常满意
I appreciate the make up so much,
谢谢你
thank you!
好 不客气…
You're welcome.
谢谢你…
Thank you…
来宾亲友请起立
Please stand up.
先人灵柩升出礼堂
Please move the coffin to the centre of the hall.
请依照本馆员工引导…
Please follow our instruction…
瞻仰遗容最后一面
to show the last respect to the dead.
以下是盖棺仪式
The coffin is going to be closed,
来宾亲友请起立
please stand up.
面向门外
Face to the door.
盖棺
Cover the coffin.
哇 不错嘛!
It's great!
这么快就适应我们殡仪馆的生活了
You've already adapted the life of here.
真棒
It's great!
怎么样?洗完手当然就可以吃了
After washing hands,then I can eat.
百无禁忌嘛
I don't have to worry anything.
有没有人知道阿堂在哪儿?
Have you seen Shishedo?
打电话到家里也没人有人接
I can't reach him by phone,
也不请个病假 搞什么?
he didn't apply sick leave or anything.
再怎么样 他的偶像死了
Anyways,his idol died,
可能他去找朋友散散心…
maybe he is going for a tour…
应该不会有事啦
with some friends to cheer himself up.
那肾亏呢?
How about Sun-kwai?
到澳门赌钱了
He went to Macau for gambling.
Call我的
It's my call.
电话借我用一下
Please lend me your phone.
谢了
Thank you.
喂 Daviv啊?
Daviv?
是啊
Yes.
好…我马上就来 拜拜
Alright,I'll be right there,bye bye.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起了各位 有事我要先走了
I am leaving now,bye bye.
华哥来了!
It's the loan shark Wah!
肾亏 百搭
Hi,Sun-kwai,Trump.
华哥 早…
Good morning.
你们怎么好像很怕我啊
Are you afraid of me?
我这么有气质!
I am a gentleman,
你看 西装毕挺的
see,I am wearing suit!
干你娘!是谁乱丢东西啊?
Damn it,who threw things down?
华哥 这里经常有东西扔下来的
Someone is used to throw things down.
是吗?
Really?
对了 华哥
Hi,brother Wah,
这么早是不是要去运动啊?
are you going for a morning exercise?
不是啊!
No,
收钱当然要早一点!对吧?
I come to collect money!
华哥
Wah,
最近全香港的经济好像不太景气
you know the Hong Kong economy is getting worse.
我知道
I know.
我有钱的时候
When I had money,
董事长就叫我不要买房子
the executive asked me not to buy property.
剩一点点钱呢他叫我买股票
When I had a little money,he asked me to buy shares.
说什么会涨 结果全套牢了
That's why my money is frozen by the stock market.
他就是这样说
Me too!Much of my money
所以害我也套牢了
is frozen in the stock market.
对啊!…
That's right.
就是!
Yeah!
他说的话比我阿昌说的话更无聊!
Cut the bull shit!
不过你放心 以你们的专业地位
Don't worry,I have confidence on you.
比那些高官更叫人有信心啦!
You are professional.
起码死人不会受你们骗!对吧?
At least,the dead people won't be cheated by you!
没钱还不要紧 还一点点利息就好
Maybe,you can return some interest to me.
利息?利息有…
Interest?I've got it.
华哥
Brother Wah.Take it please.
华哥 请笑纳
Take it please.am sorry.
好像还差一点点啊!
I think you still owe me some.
最近没有孝子可以客串
I don't have any moon-lighting job lately,
收入有限
so I don't earn much.
经济比较不好啊!
Poor business!
对了 阿昌啊
Cheong.
是
Yes.
现在你的兄弟有难啊
Your buddies are in need of help,
你够不够义气啊?
do you have righteousness?
当然够啦!
Sure I have.
够就帮他们还一点点嘛
So,just give them a hand.
这没问题…
Yes…
真的够义气!
You are a righteous man!
二十元 你这样就算够义气?
What?Just $20 dollars,
你他妈耍我啊?
are you fooling me?
我没耍你啊华哥
No,I am not fooling you.
我是耍他们
I am fooling them only.
不是啊华哥 开玩笑的…
No,brother Wah,it's just a joke…
他还有的…
He has money…
没有了没了…
Any more?
别碰我…
Don't touch me.
拿出来吧!
Take it out please.
有没有毛病?扔完一件又一件
What's the world coming to!
一点功德心都没有
How can people throw a chopper out of the window?
扔死你们谁还我钱?对吧?
If you are killed,who will pay my money back?
要不要我上去教训教训他?
Do you want me to teach them a lesson?
当然要啊!
Sure!
见义勇为是你这种英雄做的嘛
It's the thing a hero should do,
华哥
Brother Wah,go ahead.
当然啦!助人为快快收本嘛
Sure!I love to help!
我上去帮你教训他!
Let me go up and teach them a lesson now.
华哥 看你的了…
Thank you…
我上去教训他!
I'm going right now.
开门!
Open the door!
有胆扔东西没胆子开门吗?开门…
You dared to throw but daren't you open the door?
什么人乱扔东西?
Who threw the knief?
什么人?
Who is it?
站住!
Freeze!
老太婆
Grimalkin,
东西是不是你丢的?
did you throw the chopper to the street?
我跟你讲话啊!
Answer me!
为什么对老人家这么没礼貌?!
Why aren't you impolite to the old people?
华哥
Brother Wah.
怎么样?
Are you alright?
没事!
I am fine!
那个混蛋让我打得啊…
I gave that bastard…
连他妈都认不出来了
I gave that bastard a great lesson.
华哥 为什么不把他拖下来…
Why didn't you take him down,
然后再海扁他一顿?
let us teach him one more lesson?
是啊…
Yeah…
算啦!
Be merciful.
对了 我约了人看电影 下次再见
I've got a date,see you next time.
我先走了 拜拜
See you.Bye bye.
拜拜
Bye bye.
小姐 别站在那里
Miss,don't stand over there,
那里很危险的
it's dangerous.
过来
Come here.
这上面常常有东西丢下来
Someone always throw things down,
好危险的 快过来
it's dangerous to stand there.Come here.
对啊
Come.
快点!
Hurry up!
那上面有那个啊 真的
It's spooky up there.
我知道
I know it.
你知道?
What?
房子是我妈的
That's my mom's house.
她死了之后房子就是我的
She died,then it goes to me.
我刚刚才从加拿大回来
I've just come back from Canada.
我刚从殡仪馆出来
I just come out from the funeral home,
你好
how are you?
我叫阿昌
Call me Cheong,
专门替人做法事超渡的
I do the sacrificial ceremony for the dead.
这上面有一些脏东西
Your mom's spirit is over there,
应该是你的先人觉得不舒服
it means she doesn't feel well.
也就是你妈妈觉得不舒服
So she comes back.
我想是我妈回来了
I think she is back.
她生前喜欢从上面丢东西
She loved throwing things out of window when she was alive.
那么就应该多烧点金银大屋给你妈
So,you should burn some paper sacrificial gifts to her.
先人就不会骚扰生人了
So,she won't disturb the living descendants.
大概要多少钱啊?
How much should I spend?
小姐 大伙很投缘!
Miss,it's fate for us to meet,
我们也很老实啊!
we will charge you the lowest price.
对…
Right…
一万多块钱 很便宜的
Just around ten thousand,it's rather cheap.
一万多块钱是订金
Ten thousand is the deposit,
全套服务大概要两万多块
the total sum is around $20,000.
但是纸扎品另外算
For the paper sacrificial gifts,you'd pay separately.
如果想你老妈开心点 就多付两成
If you want your mom to be happy,pay more.
这样有效吗?
Does it work?
当然有效啦!
Sure!
这种事情有几千年的历史了
Such ceremony has been done for over thousands of years.
要不然怎么会流传到现在呢?
Otherwise,the modern people will not do it.
对呀…
That's right.
我看这样好了 你准备好就传呼我
Well,if you are ready,please call me.
我现在住在亲戚家里
I am now living in my relative's home.
谢谢你 小姐
Thank you,Miss.
哪里 那我先走了
Thank you.I am leaving now.
拜拜
Alright.Bye bye.
小姐再见 小姐我们很老实!…
We will charge you the lowest price!
你很老实?一万多块?
Will you?Ten thousand?Lowest price?
肾亏 待会我唱破狱灵章的时候
Sun-kwai,when I sing,
你只要记得开口闭口就行了
just open your mouth and pretend singing,
你常常忘了歌词
since you always forget the lines!
把气氛都破坏掉了
You'll ruin the atmosphere.
我知道怎么做了!
I know.
师傅…
Master…
张小姐 你好
How are you,Miss Cheung.
你好
How are you?
我们在等你呢
We are waiting for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
另外 请过目
Please take a look at the bill.
这里全部加起来要三万八千八?
What?The total is $38,800?
够便宜了吧?
Isn't it cheap enough?
小姐 我们很老实!
We charge the lowest price.
十六比九的阔银幕大电视…
Your mom would be happy…
你老妈看了准开心的
to receive such a big TV set.
这样吧 待会我们做法事的时候…
When we are praying,
你要诚心一点…
just be sincere.
记得诚心一点 诚心烧衣就是了
Remember,be sincere and burn the paper money.
因为我们还要做另外一场法事
We are going to do another ceremony,
所以我们现在就开始好不好?
shall we start now?Let's start now.
好!
Alright.
请准备
Ready.
茫茫酆都中 重重金刚山
In hell,numerous mountains are rounding the souls up.
灵宝无量光 洞照炎池烦
The light of Buddha is shining.
三魂并七魄 身随香云旛
The spirits and souls are following the flags.
定慧青莲花 往生神仙界
The green lotus of wisdom will lead you to heaven.
妈?!
Mom!
我妈她来了
My mom is back.
真的?
Really?
你妈真的回来了?
Is your mom back?
是啊 她在啊
Yes,she is here.
三万八千多花的真值得啊 张小姐
So,it worths to pay us,Miss Cheung.
不如我们多唱一次就结束了啊?
Let's pray one more time,OK?
好不好?
OK?
好…
Alright…
来 预备啦!
Ready.
茫茫酆都中 重重金刚山
In hell,numerous mountains are rounding the souls up.
灵宝无量光 洞照炎池烦
The light of Buddha is shining.
三魂并七魄 身随香云旛
The spirits and souls are following the flags.
定慧青莲花 往生神仙界
The green lotus of wisdom will lead you to heaven.
好了 张小姐
Miss Cheung,
我们还要赶下一场的法事
we are going to leave for another ceremony.
大家都很开心嘛!
So,your mom is back,
你妈妈已经回来了对不对?
you must be happy,right?
那么请先付钱吧
Please pay now.
不好意思 我差点给忘了
Oh,I am sorry.
谢谢你师傅 谢谢
Thank you,master.
谢谢啦!再见
Thank you,bye bye.
再见啦!伯母
See you!Mom.
打扰了 再见了
See you,auntie,sorry for bothering.
妈 我什么都不懂
Mom,I know nothing.
今天这场法事全都是他们作的主
They are in-charging the ceremony,
说真的 今天这场法事…
but I don't think…
真不像价值三万八千多块
this worths $38,800.
如果有什么做得你不高兴不开心的话
If you don't feel good,or you don't feel happy,
你就去找他们 不要来找我
just go to them,it's none of my business.
记住 千万不要来找我!
Remember,don't come to me,mom.
妈 要保佑我!
Mom.
干杯!
Cheers!
阿昌
Cheong.
什么事啊
What?
这次我们会不会赚得太过份了?
Have we gone too far?
对啊!
I think we've cheated.
对!太过份了
Yes,we have gone too far.
把你那份拿给我…
How about returning your share to me…
让我还给她
and I'll pay her back.
你神经病啊!
Are you crazy?
我要存钱跟Elaine结婚啊
I want to save money to marry Elaine.
就是啊!
That's right.
今天只有你们三个啊
Only the three of you come here tonight?
Rock 我今天心情非常好!
Rock,I am so happy tonight.
无论如何要让我唱首歌
Let me sing a song,will you?
那就来吧
So,go ahead.
这么高兴 你要唱得好一点
You'd sing better.
当然了
Of course.
今天我实在忍不住了…
I must sing a song…
我一定要唱一首歌…
这首歌是感人肺腑荡气回肠的歌…
which is so touching…
唱歌那个不是你的朋友吗
They seem to be your friends.
是阿昌啊
It's Cheong.
3 2 1…
茫茫酆都中 重重金刚山
In hell,numerous mountains are rounding the souls up.
他唱什么?
What is he singing?
但是他唱得好像挺开心啊
He seems to be so happy.
三魂并七魄 身随香云旛
The spirits and souls are following the flags.
好了 别唱了…
No way…
不好意思…
I am sorry…
味道唱得不够是不是?
Not tough enough?
你好像前卫了一点
It's too advanced for our guests here.
好了…
It's alright.
尿急啊
I want to piss.
对不起…
I am sorry…
过来!…
Come here!
干什么?
What?
尿又急死我了!
You've driven me mad.
先过来嘛!
Come here!
你看!
See!
阿力没希望了
Lik is hopeless.
Daviv?
他怎么可以这样子呢?!
What's up?You're so corny!
要给阿红面子
Give Hung face please.
放轻松点
Relax.
我忍不住了 我要上厕所了
I can't hang on,I want to piss.
婆婆 这是男厕所啊
Granny,this is man's toilet.
这么早就做清洁了?
Early cleaning?
要清洁也应该等人家先出去嘛
But you should clean it after the customers have left.
你搞什么?
What's up?
这首歌我是点给陈大昌听的
This is dedicate to Chan Tai-cheong.
干嘛?
What?
这里有问题 很不干净
I think this place is spooky,
此地不宜久留!
it's not wise to stay any longer.
神经病?!
Are you nuts?
不好意思
I am sorry.
干嘛不好意思?
What do you mean?
我不知道你是第一次
I don't know this is your first time.
神经病 你又不是强奸我
Nuts!You're not raping me.
真是对不起
But I am really sorry.
除非呢你是打算不要我了
Unless you are not going to marry me.
通常每个男人办完事后都会抽一口烟
Usually,men will smoke after sex.
我平常不抽的 我…
I seldom smoke…
我是做完一些事才会抽的
I smoke when I finish something…
就是把手边的工作做完…
I mean…my job.
你知道我的意思嘛
Hope you'd understand.
我只抽一根香烟…还有
And I only smoke…
抽几口我就不抽了
smoke one.
我看我们去喝点东西好不好?
Let's go for a drink.
好…反正也睡不着
Alright,since I can't sleep.
好巧啊 又是这张桌子
What a coincidence!The same table!
想什么?
What are you thinking?
我在想我们的事
I am thinking about our affair.
不如我们结婚?
Let's get married.
如果讲一次我就当你是认真的了
If you repeat it,I will consider it seriously.
我们结婚吧
Let's get married.
那你家里除了你还有什么人?
Tell me your family.
我家里是开药材店的
My family runs a drugs store.
而且只有我一个儿子
I am the only son.
有一层楼 就这么多了
We have an apartment,that's it.
你呢?
How about you?
我就没你那么幸运 我是个孤儿
I am not that lucky,I am an orphan.
很小的时候养父一个人把我给带大
When I was small,my father adopted me.
你养父做什么工作?
What is your father?
化妆师啊 不过已经过世了
He was a make up artist,but he died.
不好意思
I am sorry.
没关系 能够帮死人化妆啊
Never mind,he made up for the dead,
都已经百无禁忌了
he didn't mind death.
你养父是死人化妆师?
Your father made up for the dead?
有什么问题?
What's the problem?
我也是啊 你介意吗?
Me too!Do you mind that?
不介意!怎么会介意呢?
I don't!I won't mind your job.
你不要胡思乱想啊
Don't lose your mind.
那么 我们还结不结婚?
Are we going to marry then?
当然要结啦!
Of course!
那我们要用什么形式结婚啊?
What form are we going to marry?
要请几桌啊?
How about the banquet?
你想要什么样的形式?
What do you suggest?
西式中式还是…
Western or Chinese style?
那不是要请很多次了吗?
So we have to waste much time for the arrangement.
这样好了 我们早上用中式…
And so,In the morning,Chinese style.
晚上用西式结怎么样?
In the evening,Western style.
这里怎么有那么多绳子?
Why do we have rope here?
我买的
I bought it.
你买那么大捆绳子干什么?
What for?
想用的时候就可以拿来用哪
Suddenly when you want it,you can get it easily.
你想用这些绳子来上吊啊?
For hanging yourself to death?
上吊有什么奇怪的?
It's nothing strange.
人总要死一次啊
People will die one day.
你搞什么?
What are you doing?
我只想知道我死了以后是什么样子
I just want to know how do I look when I die.
神经病!大吉大利!
You are insane!
童言无忌!
How can you fool us like this?
干什么?
What's the matter?
我怎么会弄成这个样子?
What's wrong with me?
你说想看看…
You said you want to see…
自己死的时候是什么样子
how you look when you die.
我哪有说过?
I didn't say that!
呸…
Holy shit…
赶快擦干净了
Clean your face now,
样子吓死人了
you almost scare the shit out of me.
惨啦 我怎么把自己弄成这个样子?
Holy shit!Why did I do this to myself?
越看越难看
It's ugly looking!
难看那就别看了!
So,just don't look at it.
干嘛!
What's up?
什么事?
What's the matter?
昨天你们不是说我不对劲的吗?
Yesterday,you said I was weird,didn't you?
但是你不是说没事吗
But you said you are alright.
你信不信?
Don't you believe it?
我当然相信啦!因为你是我大哥
Of course,you are always my boss.
你呢百搭?
How about you,Trump?
被逼相信
I am forced to believe.
信就信 不信就不信
What do you mean to be forced to believe?
什么叫被逼相信?
我常常逼你还钱
I always force you to pay my money back,
你常常说过几天过几天还
why didn't listen to me?
我只有被逼相信啦!
So I am forced to belive you.
我告诉你们
I tell you something.
我觉得我自己有些不对劲
I really think that there is something wrong with me.
有什么不对劲?
What's wrong?
哪里啊?
How do you feel?
我觉得…
I feel that…
又怎么了?
What's the matter?
我觉得那个老太婆在跟着我
I feel that the granny is following me.
我看我们把钱还给她好了
Why not return money to her?
把钱还给她?
Return the money?
反应怎么这么强烈?!
Why did you react like that?
要不然怎么办?
Or,what should we do?
那个老太婆会找我们的
The granny will come to us.
不是找我们 是找你而已
No,she will come to you only.
那你们两个是不理我了?
Are you going to leave me alone?
不是不理你 再观察一天
No,let's wait and see for one more day.
可能是你疑神疑鬼
Maybe,you are too sensitive.
如果我们把钱还给她
If we return her money now,
那我们不是吃亏了吗?
we may be dump-bell.
那倒是
That's right.
如果疑神疑鬼
If Cheong's just over sensitive,
就把钱还给她岂不太笨了?
it'll be foolish of us to pay her back.
那我们就富贵险中求
Well,let's take risk
我们三兄弟一起多冒一天的险
for one more day.
是你多冒一天的险!
It's you who is going to take risk.
你干嘛跑这里来?
Why are you here?
对啊 我怎么会在这里啊?
Why am I here?
还不出来?
Come out now.
阿昌!刚才为什么用手来吓我?
Yes,why did you scare me?
我只是手毛多了一点罢了
I have hairy hands,
怎么会吓倒你啊?
but how can it scare you?
你们两个在吵什么东西?
Why are you fighting?
他无缘无故跑到我房间里面来
He sneaked into my room.
你干嘛无缘无故跑到他房间睡?
Why didn't you stay in your own room?
我也不知道为什么
I sneaked into his room only!
无缘无故会跑到他房间来的
No big deal.I was sleeping,
我醒来就在他床下了
but I didn't know why I slept under his bed.
我看是你把我抬来的!
Did you take me in?
谁有空抬你进来!
I am not that nonsense to take you in.
还不走?!
Aren't you leaving now?
我偷窥你纹身啊?
I don't think I came in to peep at your tattoo.
半夜三更吵个不停
Why don't you shut up?
你这么会在这儿?
Why are you here?
对呀!我怎么会在这儿?
Why am I here?
你真是有神经病!
You're crazy!
自己房间不睡却在这儿睡…
Why didn't you sleep in your own room?
阿昌啊?
Where is Cheong?
真的好像有点不对劲
He seems to be obsessed.
你们俩进来干什么?
Why do you come in?
阿昌 你真的好像有点不对劲
Cheong,you seem to have something wrong.
真的有点不对劲啊
You have something wrong.
不对劲?没有 没什么不对劲啊
No,I don't think so.
别妨碍我睡觉 出去吧
Stop bothering me,go out.
没事就好了
I am glad you are fine.
下次再进来…
If you come in again…
就再也出不去了
You can never go out.
开个玩笑而已!
I am just kidding.
开玩笑!
Damn it!
出去!快出去!
Go out!Go.
什么事啊?
What's the matter?
百搭 你有没有听到什么声音?
Trump,did you hear anything?
我好像听到
I think I heard something.
那怎么办?
What'll we do?
去看看吧
Go and take a look.
阿昌!
Cheong.
你搞什么?
What are you doing?
你不要自杀呀
Don't commit suicide.
不可以这个样子!
Don't scare us!
我先打电话给阿力
I'll call Lik.
你到那里去啊?快回来
Where are you going to?
我打电话给阿力啊!
I am going to give Lik a call.
不行 你回来 我撑不住了!
Come back,I can't hang on.
我打电话给阿力救命呀!
I am calling for help!
你先回来 帮我把他扶着
Come back first,hold him please.
放他下来再说!你再打电话给阿力
Take him down first.
好…
Alright.
什么事?
What's the matter?
阿昌他撞鬼了
Cheong is being obsessed.
快来 阿力…
Lik,come now,Lik,come!
大法师?
The Exorcist?
他像大法师吗?
Does he look like an exorcist?
他不像大法师
No,
他像大法师里面被鬼缠身的那一个
he is like the girl in the movie.
鬼缠身…
Obsessed…
阿昌!
Cheong!
阿昌 你没事吧?
Are you alright?
她在我里面不肯走啊
She is with me,she doesn't want to leave me.
她在里面?
Is she inside?
谁在你身体里面?
Who is inside?
那个老太婆啊!
The granny.
老婆婆 你可不可以先出来?
Granny,can you come out?
你不要骚扰我朋友好不好?
Don't bother my friend,will you?
是啊…
Yeah…
我不认识你 你快走
I don't know you,leave now.
走吧
Let's go.
那你认识我朋友吗?
You know my friend?
不认识
No.
不认识为什么要缠住他?
So why do you bother him?
有条绳子捆着我
There is a rope rounding my neck,
我不舒服
I don't feel comfortable.
我要找替身
I want him to replace me.
可是你要找替身也不应该找我朋友啊
But you don't need my friend,do you?
对啊!
Yeah!
你朋友说要给我消灾
Your friend said he could make me feel ease.
可是每件事情你都做好
But he didn't do it properly.
不好意思…
I am sorry…
走…
Go…
你们几个混蛋到底干了什么?
What did you do?
就为她做了一场法事啊
We just did a sacrificial ceremony for her.
做场法事?就这么简单吗?
Just this?
是啊
Yeah.
有没有敛财啊?
Did you cheat her money?
有!
Yes.
现在骗都已经骗了 该怎么办啊?
But,what'll we do now?
我说了几遍了?死人的钱是不能骗的
I told you many times,you can't cheat the dead.
那怎么办?
So,what should we do now?
还给人家啊?!
Return the money.
那些钱花的花 还的还
But,I spent quite a lot of money,
剩下的钱都在阿昌那边啊
Cheong has got the rest.
他现在这个样子也拿不到啊?
But,I don't think he can get my money back now.
那怎么办?
So?
你可不可以帮我们先垫一下
Please pay it for us.
什么?要我先垫?
What?
你这么不把手指头插到插座里头…
You made the mess
看会不会电死你!要我先垫?
and you want me to pay for you!
拜托了 帮个忙了好不好!
Come on,please help!
来嘛…
Come on!
好了…
Alright…
先还钱吧!
Pay the money back first.
电话 那女人的电话
The number,the woman's phone number.
GiGi?
看住他呀
Take care of him.
老婆婆 你放过他吧
Granny,please let him go,
你放过阿昌吧好不好?
please let him go,
不要再吓我们了
please don't scare us.
我好难过!
I am dying!
阿力已经去帮我们还钱了
Lik is going to return the money for us.
是啊!
Yeah.
你没事吧?
Are you alright?
你是不是阿昌呀?
Are you Cheong?
我好难过!
I am dying!
阿昌…
Cheong…
没事…
It's fine…
你先撑一下!
Hang on!
肾亏 你干什么?
Are you crazy?
你这样想插死阿昌吗?
Do you want to kill Cheong?
不要这样!
Please don't!
肾亏 你干嘛?
Sun-kwai,how is it?
肾亏 你干什么?
Sun-kwai,what's wrong?
肾亏…
Sun-kwai…
你干什么?救命呀!
What are you doing?Help!
肾亏 你干什么?
Sun-kwai,what are you doing?
他不是肾亏
He isn't Sun-kwai,
他让老婆婆上身了 快走
he is obsessed by the granny.
快点用沙发压住他
Lock him up by the sofa.
砍他呀!
Kill him!
这样会砍死肾亏的
No,I will kill Sun-kwai!
砍他啊 你还等什么?
Kill him,what are you waiting for?
我砍不下手啊
I can't!I just can't!
他不是肾亏
He isn't Sun-kwai,
他是老婆婆 砍他呀
he is obsessed by that granny,kill him.
我叫你砍啊!砍啊!
I told you to kill him!Go ahead!
百搭 阿昌 我是肾亏啊
Trump,Cheong,this is Sun-kwai!
我是肾亏啊
I am Sun-kwai!
你是肾亏?
Are you Sun-kwai?
是呀
Yes.
你有没有欠我钱?
Do you owe me money?
没有
No.
没有?他就是老太婆 砍他…
No?He is the granny,kill him…
有…
Yes,I do owe you money.
欠多少?
How much do you owe me?
三万八千二百四十
US$38,240.00
错!砍他!
Wrong,kill him.
还有两毛…
And twenty cents.
答对了 他是肾亏!
He is Sun-kwai.
没事了 大家没事了
It's fine!We are fine!
把沙发抬开
Take up the sofa,take it up.
没事了!
It's fine!
怎么了肾亏?
How are you?
没事了…
I am fine…
肾亏 我差点砍死你!
Sun-kwai,I have almost killed you.
没事了!
It's fine!
老太婆呢?
Where is the granny?
怎么搞的 停电了?
Why the electricity is cut?
保险丝烧了还是没交电费啊?
Is it because of the fuse or didn't you pay the bill?
我怎么知道?
How do I know?
百搭你去看看
Trump,go and take a look.
你去看吧 肾亏
Go and take a look!
阿昌 你去看看
You do it,Cheong.
胆小鬼!
You nuts!
这样吧 我们一起去看
Let's go together.
好啊
Alright.Let's go.
你是肾亏
You're Sun-kwai.
你是百搭
You are Trump.
我是百搭
I am Trump.
你是肾亏
You're Sun-kwai.
我是肾亏 你是百搭
I am Sun-kwai,you are Trump.
上你的身了!
You're obsessed!
不 我是百搭
No,Trump,I am Trump.
你是老婆婆
You're granny.
你别装了 你才是老婆婆
Stop pretending,you're the granny.
老婆婆 你的演技还挺好的
Granny,you are a good actress!
我们照一下就知道了…
I will know it by lighting you up…
肾亏
Sun-kwai!
对不起啊!
I am terribly sorry!
阿昌 没事了!
Cheong,it's fine!
肾亏!
Sun-kwai.
真是不好意思啊
I am really sorry.
电话
The phone!
阿力呀?
It's Lik.
阿力?让我讲
Lik?Let me talk to him.
阿力 她还在 老婆婆还在
Lik,she is still here!
她还在缠我们
She is around us.
对呀 快帮我们摆平她
Go and fix it please.
张小姐 你妈的坟墓在哪里啊?
Miss Cheung,where is the tomb of your mom?
郑先生 这么晚了还要去祭我妈啊?
Mr.Cheng,why do you want to worship her so late?
实不相瞒 其实我有几个朋友…
Be frank,my friends…
在上个星期为你妈做了一场法事
did a sacrificial ceremony for your mom.
可能是他们骗了你的钱
They cheated your money,
所以你妈正在骚扰他们
so your mom is bothering them.
老婆婆躲在哪里呢?
Where does she hide?
在哪里呢?
Where?
不关我的事 别出来!
None of my business!
别紧张 冷静一点
Stay calm!
不要疑神疑鬼
Stay calm.
老婆婆可能已经走了
Granny may have gone.
肾亏 你干嘛要砍我?
Sun-kwai,why do you chop me?
你是老婆婆 不是阿昌
You're granny,you are not Cheong.
你疯了!你砍我才是老婆婆呢
You are crazy!
我是阿昌呀
I am Cheong.
不是 你是老婆婆不是阿昌
No,you are granny,you're not Cheong.
我一看你的眼神就知道你是老婆婆了
I can tell it from your eyes.
慢着
Wait.
百搭 你干嘛要敲他?
Trump,why did you knock his head?
你说呢?
What do you think?
继续上他的身别出来…
Obsess him,don't come out…
为什么继续上他的身叫她别出来?
Why do you ask her not to come out?
要不然她会上我们的身了
Of course,if she comes out,she will obsess us.
快帮忙吧!
Come and help!
继续上他的身别出来…
Obsess her,don't come out…
对不起…
Sorry…
救命啊!
Help!
没事…先起来
It's fine!Get up!
救命啊!
Help!Mom,help me!
帮我拿着它!
Take this first.
不好意思…
I am sorry.
对不起 我不是故意的
I don't mean it.
对不起 我们是无心的…
I am sorry.
该走那边啊?
Where to go?
你妈的坟在哪里?你怎么问我!
Where is your mom's tomb?
这边…
This way…
继续上他的身别出来…
Stay in him and don't come out…
我不够了 快去捡一点给我
Get more for me.
继续上身别出来…
Stay inside his body and don't come out.
肾亏!
Sun-kwai!
继续上身别出来…
Stay inside his body and don't come out!
Stay inside…
这些符都没画啊
These charms are not written!
拿给你让你扔我啊?
Don't you think I am stupid to let you hurt me?
她上了肾亏的身了 快走!
Run!Hurry up!She's obsessed him!
百搭 找东西来把门锁起来
Trump,lock the door.
找什么东西啊?
How?
快点!动脑筋啊
Use your brain!
别走那么快啊
Don't run that quickly.
Gigi小姐
Miss Gigi,
这个坟好像很久没有人拜祭过了
this tomb hasn't been tidied up for a long time.
是不是这个啊?
Isn't it your mom's tomb?
让我看看
Let me check it.
阿昌 我找到东西来顶门了
Cheong,I've found something to lock it up.
快呀!我撑不住了!
Hurry up!I can't stand it anymore!
让开…
Give way…
是我妈的坟
This is my mom's tomb.
真的是你妈的坟?
Really?
是啊
Yes,it is.
好了 终于找到了
Fine!We've finally got it.
把香给我
Give me the incense.Thank you.
打火机
Lighter please.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么会有根红绳子?
Why there is a red rope?
对啊!
Yeah!
难怪你妈说…
That's why your mom said…
有根绳子缠住她脖子不舒服!
she felt uncomfortable.
妈 是我不孝…
Mom,I am not filial!
我去了加拿大那么久…
I went to Canada
都没来看你
and didn't come back to visit you.
妈 对不起
Mom,I am sorry.
求求你 放过我们啊
I beg you!Please let us go.
你这是干什么?我是肾亏啊
What are you doing?I am Sun-kwai.
绳子甩掉了
The rope is gone!
我走了!
I am leaving now!
你们以后别再骗人了
Don't you ever cheat again!
我是阿力 你们现在怎么样了?
This is Lik,how is it now?
没事 没事了
We are fine!
真的没事?
Really?
老婆婆走了
The granny has gone.
真的?
Really?
那个东西上身有什么感觉啊?
How did you feel of being obsessed?
干这行这么多年…
By the way,
还没遇上过那个东西
I haven't experienced that.
好厉害!
It's great!
同一时间三个家伙
She obsessed three bodies at the same time.
不过下次别忘了魔姐的份儿!
Next time,don't forget to ask her to join you.
阿力 你的话还真多啊
Lik,stop that nonsense please.
说得整个殡仪馆的人都知道了
Everyone in the funeral home knows it.
那倒不是
Not exactly.
那些死尸不知道
Those dead bodies don't know anything.
红姐 这里啊
Sister Hung,here we are.
待会儿不要乱说话 记住
Mind your tongue please.OK.
知道了!
Alright.
塞车 你们三个没事吧?
Are you alright?
没事
We are fine!
没事就是有事
So,you've had problem.
阿红 我刚刚看到一件礼物
Hung,I bought a present,
我想你会喜欢所以就买来送你了
it's nice,I think you'll like it.
很好看啊
It's pretty.
漂亮!
It's really pretty.
谢谢
Thank you.
对了 我有事情要宣布
I have something to tell you.
我就快要结婚了
I am going to marry.
要送贺礼啊?
So we have to send you present.
我又要多吹一天了
I have to work one more day.
乱说话?
Come on!
那个长期饭票是谁啊?
Who is the lucky guy?
D.A.V.I.V.
Daviv?
你的 包大包一点啊
It's yours,don't forget your present.
阿昌 你的
Cheong,it's yours.
Ann 你的
Ann,this is yours.
谢谢红姐
Thank you.
肾亏
Sun-kwai.
谢谢
Thank you.
百搭
Trump.
恭喜
Congratulations.
没想到这次来真的
Are you kidding?
八卦 我跟你讲我要结婚了
I mean it,I am going to marry.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
早些到啊 谢谢
Come and join the banquet.
恭喜
Congratulations.
我要结婚了 你们都也有啊!
You are being invited too.
谢谢…红姐
Thank you.
和记一三八台
Station 138.
麻烦你 1077
Account 1077 please.
哪位来电?
May I know your name?
阿红 先前我就留了一通了
Hung,I left a message before.
请问对方他回Call没有?
Has the account holder returned call yet?
还没有
Not yet.
有货到了
Here comes the body.
来…我来验货啊
Let me check it.
让我看看
Let me see.
怎么会这样?
Oh my God!
真是的!这个大有来头啊!
Stay calm!This is the famous Charcoal!
四大金刚之一的黑炭头 难搞了吧?
This is the famous Charcoal!Difficult job,huh?
这个是比较难搞
Yes,
搞一下就习惯了
but you'll be used to it.
不搞行不行啊?
May I be excused?
什么东西难搞啊?
What's scaring you?
她害怕
She is scared.
我搞不定了
I can't handle it,Hung.
我来好了
Let me do it.
你跑到什么地方去了?
Where have you been?
我整晚都在等你啊
I've been waiting for a night.
是这样!我最近好忙啊
I am damn busy in these days!
每天忙到很晚才回家
不会吧?
Are you kidding me?
忙到连一通电话都不打给我
Why can't you just return a call?
我Call了你一个礼拜
I've called you for a week,
你也不回电话
you don't even give me a call.
打电话到你家都是电话录音
Only your tape recorder answers my call.
对不起 我真的忙死了
I am sorry,I am real busy.
酒楼那边打电话过来
The manager of the restaurant called,
说要先付订金
he wants us to pay the deposit.
我明天就去 明天就去
I'll go tomorrow.
不用了 我已经付过了
I've paid it already.
他们是希望我们确定要请几桌
They want us to confirm how many tables we want.
你那边要请几桌啊?
How many tables do you want?
这件事晚点再说
Let's talk about it later,OK?
我有个很重要的电话
I have an important call to make,
我要上去打
I have to go up right now.
我明天再找你
I'll call you tomorrow.
干什么?
What's up with you?
你到底怎么了?
What's up?
我想我们不要结婚
Let's forget our wedding.
为什么?
Why?
你不要问了 我不想讲嘛
Don't ask me,I don't want to talk about it.
Daviv 你等一下
What are you doing?
怎么样?碰你一下都不行吗?
Are you afraid of being touched by me?
你不要摸我啦!
Don't touch me!
我受不了你的手…
I can't stand you touching the corpse…
摸过尸体以后再来摸我…
and then touch me…
我真的好不舒服!
I feel so bad!
我觉得我自己也是
I feel like touching the corpse!
什么?可是你说过…你不介意
You said you don't mind it.
我只是不想伤你的心
I just don't want to hurt you.
我试过叫自己不介意
I tried to tell myself not to care about it,
但…我办不到 我真的办不到!
but…I can't!I just can't!
为什么你不早点跟说?
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
现在喜帖都发出去了
I've sent out the invitation cards,
我们不可以不结婚
I can't cancel the wedding!
那样子我会没脸见人的!
I will have no face!
对不起…
I am sorry…
Daviv 我们照样结婚
Daviv,let's get married.
明天我就辞职不干
Tomorrow,I just go back and resign.
你不要不跟我结婚好不好!Daviv!
Do marry me please.
你不要这样子!
Come on!
我求求你 你不要再跟着我
I beg you!Don't follow me,
我求求你 不要再跟着我了!
I beg you!
阿堂?
Shishedo?
你回来了?
You're back!
你哪儿去了?
Where have you been?
那么久没见我们都好担心你
I worry so much about you!
阿堂!
Shishedo!
阿堂呀!
真的走了?!
You've gone!
阿堂!
Shishedo!
为什么?为什么连你都怕我?
Why?Why are you afraid of me?
Daviv说怕我他就要避开我
David leaves me,
你呢?
how about you?
我们是自己人 为什么要避开我?
We are a family!Why do you stay away from me?
为什么?…
Why?
为什么你要走?
Why do you want to leave me?
每个都说害怕不干
Everyone says they are afraid of serving the dead.
那我一个人做好了
OK,I will do it.
没有人理我
No one cares about me!
我不想一个人
I don't want to be alone.
我也需要别人理我
I want someone to care about me.
不要扔下我
Don't leave me alone.
我真的觉得好累!
I am really tired!
这蛋糕看起来好好吃啊
I love this cake very much.
说真的 那玫瑰花真够漂亮的
The rose is really pretty.
肾亏
Sun-kwai!
红姐 今天是你的生日
Today is your birthday,
我祝你旗开得胜
wish you win every races.
什么旗开得胜 你真土啊!
What's that shit!You're nonsense!
万寿无疆嘛
You'd say long life to Hung!
说什么都没关系!
Anything will do!
红姐 来鞠个躬
Come on,I'd like to bow to you.
呸
Shit!
这是生日啊?
What's wrong with you?
无所谓啦!百无禁忌嘛
It doesn't matter!I don't care about it.
好了 先干一杯再说吧
Alright,let's say cheers!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
谢谢…
Thank you…
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
大家干杯!
Cheers!
阿红 吹蜡烛吧
Hung,come on,make a wish.
对了 Daviv呢?
Where is Daviv?
他今天有重要事情要办
He has something important to do.
重要得连我的生日都没办法出席了
So,he can't attend my birthday party.
你们两个在那边干什么?
What's wrong with you two?
说悄悄话啊?
阿红过生日
Lik,
阿力一定要唱首歌祝贺她是不是?
you should sing on Hung's birthday.
唱歌…
Come on!
唱什么歌
Sing a song for us.
红姐的那首招牌歌
Sing Hung's favourite song.
我唱歌真的很难听啊
I sing awfully!
没关系 好玩嘛
It doesn't matter,just for fun,come on.
就是 没关系啊
Come on!
唱歌…
Sing us a song!
我在这里小声唱可不可以?
How about singing here?
唱歌!
Sing now!
[[时光一去永不回[[
[[Time flies and never return.[[
[[往事只能回味[[
[[The past will only be treasured in your dreams.[[
[[忆童年时竹马青梅[[
[[Remember those days in the past?[[
[[两小无猜日夜相随[[
[[We grew up together.[[
[[春风又吹红了花蕾[[
[[The Spring breeze makes the flowers blossom.
[[你也已经添了新岁[[
[[You've grown up.[[
[[你就要变心[[
[[If you want to dump me,[[
[[像时光难倒回[[
[[it's like time never returns.[[
[[我只有在梦里相依偎[[
[[I will be with you in my dreams only.[[
[[往事只能回味[[
[[I can only treasure the past in my dreams.[[
有主归主无主归西!
Let the dead find his place.
不要走嘛 不要那么早走
Don't leave now!
再多玩一会好不好
Let's stay for a while.
红姐生日嘛
It's Hung's birthday.
对啊
That's a good idea.
来嘛
Come on.
玩什么?
What shall we play?
我带你们去一个很正点的地方
I'll take you to a nice place.
如果不正点的话
If it isn't nice,
就要退钱啊
you'd give me back my share.
有没有东西喝啊?
Anything to drink?
让我来
Let me do it.
快点啊!
It's great.
玩什么嘛?
What'd we play now?
娘娘腔似的!
You're sissy!
谁Call你啊?
Who called you?
Elaine找我 她爷爷进了医院
Elaine called me,her grandpa is now in hospital.
我不去了 我先走了
I am leaving now.
我载你去
I'll give you a ride.
不用 我坐计程车就可以了
No,I'll take the taxi.
走了
See you then.
别怪我没提醒你
Let me remind you.
对Elaine好一点
Be good to Elaine,
难得她不介意你做这一行
it's rare that she doesn't mind your work.
我知道了 生日快乐
Sure I know it.
拜拜
Bye bye.
这儿真正点!
This is a nice place!
我在楼下吹音乐吹了那么久
I have played music downstairs for such a long time.
还不知道有这么好的地方
I don't even know this place.
红姐 你怎么找到这么好的地方?
How did you find this place?
不知道 是Daviv他带我来的
Daviv took me here.
红姐 我告诉你啊
I've made a nice gown.
我已经订了一件晚礼服
去喝你跟Daviv的喜酒啊
For your wedding party.
Daviv?!
红姐 你喜欢的话
Sister Hung,if you want,
可以叫Rock在你结婚的喜宴上
you can ask Rock and his band…
找队乐队助助兴啊
to play music during your wedding.
没问题!
No problem.
不过千万别叫阿力唱歌
But never ask Lik to sing.
刚才是你拉我上去
You asked me to sing,
不是我自己要唱的
I didn't intend to sing.
Rock的意思不在于你自己愿意唱
Rock doesn't mean that,
或者是别人拉你上去唱
重点是你歌唱得很难听
the point is,you sing badly!
对!就是这个意思
Right,this is the point!
我的大腿内侧好痒啊
I feel itchy!
我撞到后脑勺了
I hurt my head!
活该
Serve you right.
都是你 讲你唱歌都倒霉
It's your fault!
阿力
Lik.
阿力 不要理他们
Forget about their complaints!
有机会 好好唱一次给我听
If you have chance,sing better to me.
刚才我偷了几瓶红酒
I stole a bottle of wine,
要不要喝?
can we drink it now?
那我们来划拳
Let's play the guessing game.
好啊 反正大家都是自己人
Since no outsiders are here,
就来划我们的[殡仪馆]拳
let's play our own game.
好啊 殡仪馆拳!
The guessing game of the funeral home.
元宝蜡烛谁要吃?
Who wants to eat the paper money and joss sticks?
我不吃啊 你要吃
I don't want to,you have to.
两个两个谁要吃
Two have to eat.
没人吃
No one eats.
三个四个谁要吃?
Three have to eat.Four have to eat.
没人吃…
No one eats.
四个五个谁要吃?
Four have to eat.Five have to eat.
没人吃没人吃
No one eats.
我们赢啦 开酒
Five!Who is going to drink?
大吉大利 喝!
Good luck to me!Cheers!
喝!
Cheers!
谁怕谁!干杯!
喝就喝 你下次不要叫
Drink it,you should not host the next game,
我来叫好了
I'll do it.
我支持你!继续努力
I'll support you!Keep on.
元宝蜡烛谁要吃?
Who is going to eat the paper money and joss sticks?
我不吃 你要吃
You'd eat it.
两个六个谁要吃?
Two have to eat.Six have to eat.
没人吃…
No one eats…
赢了!
Bingo!
四个四个谁要吃呀?
Four have to eat.
你要吃!你要吃
You should eat,you should eat.
什么?
What?
到底是你划还是你划啊?
Why did you guess?
你叫什么?
You're not the host of this game.
元宝蜡烛谁要吃?
Who is going to eat paper money and joss stick?
我不吃 你要吃
I don't want to,you have to.
两个两个谁要吃?
Two have to eat.
喝!
Drink it!
立刻喝!
Right now.
不要赖皮!
Are you crazy?
我们喝…
Let's drink it.
四个四个谁要吃?没人吃…
Four have to eat…
两个两个谁要吃?
Two have to eat?
你要吃…
You'd eat,you'd eat.
喝啊!
Drink it.
好 喝!
Alright.
输了就要喝!
The loser should drink it.
喝!干杯
Come on,drink it.
六个六个谁要吃?
Who is going to eat?
又是你喝
It's you again!
搞什么?我不喝呀!
What's up?I don't want to drink it.
等一下…听我说几句话
Wait,I have something to tell you.
让阿红讲几句话
Let Hung say something.
虽然很老套
It's corny,
但是今天我生日 我好开心啊
but…Today is my birthday,I am so happy.
开心就抱一抱嘛!
Let's have a hug!
因为你们每个都来陪着我
Since you are staying with me tonight.
说话真老套
You're nonsense!
谢谢你 阿红
Hung,thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要好玩 不要回去嘛!
Send me home please!I am so drunk!
我还没醉啊!
I am so drunk!
阿红!
Hung!
怎么了?这么急着叫我回来
Why do you ask me to hurry back?
每个人都哭丧着脸?
What's wrong with you?
这么快就知道Elaine的爷爷死了?
You know Elaine's grandpa has passed away?
阿红死了
Hung's dead.
怎么突然会死那么多人?
Why?Why so many people died at the same time?
是不是红姐回来了?
Is Sister Hung coming back?
是
Yes.
力哥 我可不可以看看红姐?
Lik,may I take a look at Hung?
我也想
I want to see her face too.
红姐 我会把你打扮得狠漂亮
Sister Hung,I will dress you up beautifully.
阿红生前没什么亲人
Hung didn't have any relatives.
她的丧礼就靠我们了
We should help to arrange her funeral.
红姐生前对我们那么好
Sister Hung was so nice to us,
我们应该为她做点事情
we should do this thing for her.
阿力
Lik,
红姐是跳楼死的 算是死于非命
she jumped to death,
我看我们就做场法事帮她招魂
I think we should call her soul back first.
阿昌
Cheong,
你去准备一只鸡还有其它的东西
prepare a chicken and the necessary things.
我去阿红家拿件衣服
I will get a dress in her place.
[[春风又吹红了花蕾[[
[[The Spring breeze makes the flowers blossom.[[
[[你已经也添了新岁[[
[[You've grown up.[[
[[你就要变心[[
[[If you want to dump me,[[
[[像时光难倒回[[
[[it's like time never returns.[[
[[我只有在梦里相依偎[[
[[I will be with you in my dreams only.[[
红姐 回来吧
Sister Hung,come back.
回来吧 红姐
Come back,Hung.
阿力 我招不到阿红的魂魄回来
Lik,I fail to call her soul back.
你说什么?
What did you say?
你招不到她的魂魄回来?
Can't you call her soul back?
你平常收人家几万块钱你就招得到
You are paid and you can call the soul for others.
阿红她是我们的朋友啊
This is our friend!
朋友啊
Do you know what friend is?
你是不是要收钱才可以招得到?
Do you want to be paid?
我给你钱 我给你钱好不好?
Alright,I will pay you!Is that OK?
你帮我招啊!
Call her soul now!
好 我再试试
OK,I will try.
对不起
I am sorry.
阿红
Hung,
你有什么心结解不开?
what was bothering you?
要这么傻?
Why are you so silly?
居然会选择寻死?!
Why did you kill yourself?
你就这么死
Have you thought of us?
有没有想过我们的感受?
阿红
Hung,
其实我们这一群朋友都很关心你
all of us care about you so much!
为什么你不肯回来?
Why don't you come back?
难道我们只想为你做点事
Don't you appreciate
你都不领情?
what we are doing for you?
我们只不过不希望你做一只孤魂野鬼
We just don't want you to be a lonely soul.
阿红
Hung,
其实我一直都很喜欢你
I love you indeed.
你死了之后 我…
After your death,I…
我就好像孤魂野鬼一样
I am just like a lonely soul.
阿红!我求你
Hung,I beg you!
回来吧
Please come back.
阿红回来了
Hung is back.
阿红 你回来了?
Hung,you are back!
去你家干什么?
Why do we go to your home?
当然是看VCD啦!
We are going home to watch VCDs.
我刚从日本买回来十几片VCD
I have just bought many new VCDs from Japan.
香港还没有呢
It's not sold in Hong Kong yet.
我忘了拿我的皮包了
I forget my handbag.
你怎么那么糊涂!
You're clumsy!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
头!人头…
Head!I saw a head.
什么头啊?
What did you say?
什么头啊?被你吓死了
You almost scared me!
什么东西也没有
I saw nothing.
你快去拿皮包 快拿啊
Take the bag then!Go ahead.
还站在这儿干什么?走啊
Why are you standing here?Let's go.
是你车子的防盗器啦
It's your car!
走啊…
Let's go!
怎么那么邪门啊?
It won't be spooky here,I guess.
鬼呀!
Ghost!
救命啊!
Help!
上车 有鬼啊!
Shut up!There is ghost!
救命啊…鬼啊!
Help!Ghost!
开门…
Open the door!Open up!
开门呀!
Open up!
喃呒呵呢陀佛…观世音菩萨…
My God!My father in heaven…
喃呒呵呢陀佛…
holy is your name…
你很怕我吗?
Are you afraid of me?
你怕我会害你?
You worry that I would kill you?
求求你…
I beg you!
你怕我…
Are you worrying that…
抓你下去跟我结婚?
I would get you to hell to marry me?
我求求你放过我…
I beg you,let me go please.
我只想问清楚一件事
I just want to make one thing clear.
你到底有没有喜欢过我?
Have you ever loved me?
有啊…我很喜欢你啊
Yes,I love you,yes,
我真的很喜欢你啊
Yes,I love you.
还在撒谎?!
Stop lying.
我死了之后你有没有想过…
After my death,
要上炷香或鞠个躬给我
have you thought of burning incense for me?
有…我有想去殡仪馆给你上香
Yes,I do want to burn incense for you…
真的…我不敢了…
No,I dare not…
你连最后一面都不敢看
You don't even dare to see my dead body.
还说喜欢我?
How can you say loving me?
我求求你放过我…
I beg you!Let me go please.
不要再找我了 我求求你…
I beg you…
我根本不该为你死
I shouldn't have died for you.
我根本不应该为你死…
求求你不要再找我了
I beg you,let me go please.
我求求你 放过我
I beg you!Let me go!
救命啊!
Help!
不要叫!
Shut up!
走!
Let's go!
阿红
Hung.
你叫我用心唱的歌
You told me to practise that song,
我练好了
I've made it.
[[时光一逝永不回[[
[[Time flies and never returns,[[
[[往事只能回味[[
[[you can view the past in your memory.[[
[[忆童年时竹马青梅
[[When we were young,[[
[[两小无猜日夜相随[[
[[we were happy together.[[
[[春风又吹红了花蕾[[
[[The Spring breeze makes the flower blossom.[[
[[你也已经添了新岁[[
[[You've grown up.[[
[[你就要变心[[
[[If you want to fall for someone else,[[
[[像时光难倒回[[
[[I couldn't stop you[[
[[我只有在梦里相依偎[[
[[but treasure our days in my dreams only.[[
[[I will be with you in my dreams only.[[
阿红
Hung,
我记得你生前曾经说过
I remember you said once that,
你说不明白为什么…
why people can't be carefree…
一个人死了之后…
不可以潇潇洒洒的走
to face someone's death?
为什么他的家人总要哭个死去活来
Why the dead people's family would cry…
我知道你死了之后
You don't want us
也不想我们哭的死去活来
to cry for you,I know it.
可是对不起
But I am sorry.
我们真的做不到
We can't make it.
我们每个人都很想念你
All of us are going to miss you.
我们每个人都曾经为你流过眼泪
All of us cried for you.
阿红 我们今天这群朋友…
Hung,your friends have come here…
专程来送你最后一程
to see you off.
我们曾经说过 我们不会哭
We agreed that,we won't cry.
就当是我们送你的最后一份礼物
Just take it as the last present from us.
天无忌 地无忌 人无忌
Nothing should be afraid of.
溪钱旺土 百无禁忌
Paper money will bring good luck.
落葬是忌 亲朋好友转过头回避
Now,all living people should turn back.
现在大吉大利百无禁忌
It's the best time for the burial.
阿力 你看棺材放好了没有?
Lik,check whether the coffin is properly fit.
放好的话…
If yes,
用手抓把沙撒下去
catch sand by one hand and throw it on the coffin.
不要拍手
Don't clap your hands.
回去吧 走
Let's go back.
遨游天地间作品  淡淡风倾情奉献
From：Aoyou tiandijian and dandanfeng